Guide to the K.C Parsons publications collection, 1915-1999
Parsons, K.C. publications, 1915-1999
- Series: Philadelphia, PA
  - Press comments on Philadelphia's comprehensive plan & center city plan, 1960 (Box 7)
    Collection of local newspaper article reprints regarding said plans.
  - The population of Philadelphia and its metropolitan area: general characteristics and trends (public housing bulletin No. 6-A), September 1953 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Annual report 1960, January 1961 (Box 7)
  - Industrial land and facilities for Philadelphia: a report to the Philadelphia City Planning Commission, 1956 (Box 7)
    Created by University of Pennsylvania Institute for Urban Studies
  - Development programming as applied to West Philadelphia: a companion to the district plan for West Philadelphia (Technical report #8), January 1964 (Box 7)
    Created by City of Philadelphia Community Renewal Program
  - Economic base study of the Philadelphia area: planning study no. 2, August 1949 (Box 7)
  - Industrial land use plan for Philadelphia in relation to metropolitan area development: comprehensive plan report no. 1, December 1950 (Box 7)
  - Market East Plaza: a new center for transportation and commerce, May 1958 (Box 7)
  - North Triangle redevelopment area plan, September 1950 (Box 7)
  - Morton redevelopment area plan, 1958 (Box 7)
  - A review of the comprehensive plan of Philadelphia, May 1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Created by John Moses
    Xeroxed copy of student project
  - A quarter-century of retail trade activity in the Philadelphia standard metropolitan area 1929 to 1954 (public information bulletin no. 7-A), August 1958 (Box 7)
  - "Urban planning boasts a world supersalesman", July 1969 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Created by Ada Louise Huxtable
    Newspaper clipping, New York Times, July 8 1969
  - "The Philadelphia saving fund society building: a re-appraisal", October 1949 (Box 7)
    Created by Frederick Gutheim
    Reprint from Architectural Record, October 1949
  - "Philadelphia plans again: the story of the Better Philadelphia Exhibition", December 1947 (Box 7)
    Created by Architectural Forum
    Reprint from Architectural Forum; reprinted by Philadelphia City Planning Commission
  - "City in renaissance: the Philadelphia story as told by the Central Business District Association of the city of Dallas, Texas, to the people of Dallas", 1960 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Created by Dallas Central Business Association
    Reprinted by Philadelphia City Planning Commission
  - Philadelphia's plan of action for housing and neighborhood improvement, January 1955 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Created by Emil A. Tiboni
  - Philadelphia redevelopment areas, March 1961 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Map and description of areas
  - American Society of Planning Officials Newsletter: "Planning in Philadelphia and the metropolitan area", September 1954 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Created by ASPO
    Vol. 20 no. 9.
  - "Future Philadelphia as Planners See It", June 1954 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Created by Philadelphia Inquirer
    Colorama section of The Philadelphia Inquirer, Sunday June 20 1954.
  - "Philadelphia at Midstream - 1953", May 1954 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Created by Sunday Bulletin
    Special advertisement section of The Sunday Bulletin, May 2 1954.
  - Housing highlights: current activities of Philadelphia's housing and renewal agencies, January 1957 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Created by Office of the Development Coordinator
    Newsletter/bulletin/report?
  - A new approach to urban renewal for Philadelphia, March 1957 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Steps involved in acquiring and clearing land in the Morton Area, February 1957 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Report and recommendations of "ad hoc" committee on relocation, January 1956 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Created by Relocation "Ad Hoc" Committee, City of Philadelphia Redevelopment Authority
  - Itinerary, American Society of Planning Officials, September 30, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Created by APSO
    Itinerary of conference tour
  - Woodland Yards relocation site report, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Includes results of sound decibel test
  - Sections of the Philadelphia home rule charter pertaining to the Philadelphia city planning commission, 195? (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Provisions of the city charter concerning the capital program and capital budget, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Elevations and section for Defense Housing Project, Stowe Township, PA, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Created by Clarence S. Stein
    Copy of blueprint, sheet no. 7. For Federal Works Administration, Allegheny County Housing Authority
  - The greater Philadelphia story, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Created by Publications Committee of the Philadelphia Conference Committee, National Planning Conference 1954
    Brochure. Tucked inside: Newspaper article reprint, "Launch Self-Help Housing Program" by Theodore Stanford, Philadelphia Independent, September 20 1952; informational brochure for Friends Self-Help Housing Program; conference program, APSO 1954, September 26-30, 1954
- Series: southeastern/midatlantic US
  - Meeting agenda: the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill outlying properties site visit #4, November 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Created by University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill
    Packet of meeting agenda, maps of sites
  - "UNC, consultants seek input on Horace Williams, Mason Farms alternatives", December 13, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Created by University Gazette: the University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill
    Newspaper article accompanying Meeting Agenda above
  - "Consultants unveil Williams, Mason Farm plans", June 5, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Existing land use study: metropolitan Dade County, Florida, January 1961 (Box 6)
    Created by Metropolitan Dade County Planning Department
  - Shelby Farms, 1970 (Box 6)
    Includes brief letter to KC Parsons from Daniel Moore of Harland Bartholomew and Associates
  - Master plan, U.S.P.H.S. Research Park, North Carolina, March 1971 (Box 6)
    Created by A.G. Odell, Jr. & Associates; Smith, Hinchman & Grylls Associates
  - Urban renewal plan, Inner Harbor East, with revisions: draft. Baltimore, Maryland, 198? (Box 8)
    Created by Department of Housing and Community Development; Center City - Inner Harbor Development, Inc., Baltimore, Maryland
    Xeroxed copy of draft with strikeouts and revised text additions
  - Urban renewal plan, Fells Point Urban Renewal Area, with revisions: Baltimore, Maryland, 1989 (Box 8)
    Created by Department of Housing and Community Development, Baltimore, Maryland
    Xeroxed copy
  - Master plan: Baltimore county 1989-2000, February 1990 (Box 8)
    Created by Baltimore County Office of Planning and Zoning
  - Baltimore waterfront study: Fells Point and Canton urban design plan, November 1988 (Box 6)
    Created by Notter Finegold + Alexander Inc. et al.
    Prepared for Charles Center-Inner Harbor Management, Inc.
  - Anne Arundel County general development plan: Anne Arundel County, Maryland, May 1967 (Box 6)
    Created by Marcou, O'Leary and Associates et al.
  - District of Columbia comprehensive plan, 1983, August 1983 (Box 6)
    Created by D.C. Office of Planning
  - Master plan for Owings Mills new development area, May 1984 (Box 6)
    Created by County Council of Baltimore County
  - Delware preliminary comprehensive development plan, June 1967 (Box 6)
    Created by Delaware State Planning Office
  - The 1990 general plan: a six point plan for the future, Howard County, Maryland, January 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Created by Howard County Department of Planning and Zoning
    Missing binding
  - The Germantown master plan: an innovative form of new community (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Created by John Otto Matthias
    Xerox of paper submitted for presentation at the American Institute of Planners' 57th annual conference
  - Master plan for Germantown, Montgomery County, Maryland: a corridor city, October 1966 (Box 6)
    Created by The Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission
    Several large foldout maps in envelope in back
  - Comprehensive amendment to the master plan for Germantown, Montgomery County, Maryland, January 1974 (Box 6)
    Created by The Montgomery County Planning Board of the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission
  - Packet of articles on new communities (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Created by various
    Xeroxed packet of articles on Germantown (Jane A. Silverman), St. Charles Communities (R. Tennenbaum and Jay Parker), Montgomery Village (R. Tennenbaum), Greenbelt (Ken Kopstein et al.), Coldspring (R. Tennenbaum), Konterra Project Description
  - Master plan for the communities of Kensington-Wheaton, Montgomery County, Maryland: preliminary draft of amendment, July 1987 (Box 6)
  - Report 1: Physical studies, Cecil County, Maryland, November 1961 (Box 6)
  - Adopted master plan for Bowie-Collington and vicinity, Planning Areas 71 and 74, July 1970 (Box 6)
    Large foldout poster
  - Regulations for the subdivision of land for the Maryland-Washington regional district in Prince George's County, Maryland, as amended, November 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Clarksburg master plan and Hyattstown special study area: preliminary draft plan, February 1992 (Box 6)
    "A transit serviceable and pedestrian-oriented town that preserves the environment."
  - Corridor City master plan: Gaithersburg, Maryland, January 1975 (Box 6)
    Created by Gaithersburg City Planning Commission
    Includes letter of request from KC Parsons to Gaithersburg CPC; foldout maps in back pocket
  - Comprehensive plan for the national capital, August 1973 (Box 6)
    Created by Office of Planning
    Includes brochure: "How to use the District of Columbia Proposed Generalized Land Use Map"
  - A proposed amendment to the general plan for the Maryland-Washington regional district within Prince George's County, 1977 (Box 6)
    Contains 3 large map posters (Stage I-II-III) in back
  - Marina Master Plan 1989, October 1989 (Box 6)
    Created by Baltimore City Planning Department
  - Policy Plan: the countywide policy element of the comprehensive plan for Fairfax County, Virginia, August 1990 (Box 6)
    Created by Office of Comprehensive Planning
    Contains large map poster in back pocket.
  - Concept for future development and land classification system [Fairfax County, Virginia], August 1990 (Box 6)
  - General land use plan: Arlington County, Virginia, August 1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Created by Arlington County Department of Community Planning, Housing and Development - Planning Division
    Large map poster. Highlighting.
  - Selected transportation elements including the master plan of highways: Montgomery County, Maryland, April 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Large map poster.
  - The park acquisition program: Montgomery County, Maryland, January 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Clary's Forest: Columbia, Maryland, February 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Created by The Rouse Company
    Advertising pamphlet/map.
  - Dickinson: Columbia, Maryland, February 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The residential development of New Jersey: a regional approach, 1964 (Box 6)
    Created by State of New Jersey Department of Conservation and Economic Development
  - Preface to planning: a sketch plan for the Tocks Island region, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Created by Raymond and May Associates; New Jersey Division of State and Regional Planning
    Large map poster - mailing.
  - Reexamination report: Passaic, New Jersey, master plan (draft), February 1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Created by Planning Association of North Jersey
  - Summary: 1990 master plan, city of Perth Amboy, New Jersey, May 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Created by Sheehan Consulting Group et al.
  - Comprehensive amendment to the master plan for Germantown, Montgomery County, Maryland: Land use plan, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Columbia (Box 8)
    Created by Rouse Company
    Promotional folder. Contains July 1970 issue of "Columbia Today" magazine; Baltimore Street and Souvenir Map; "Visitor's Guide to Columbia"; "A Sketch of the Planning-Building Process for Columbia, Maryland" by Morton Hoppenfeld, reprinted from AIP Journal November 1967; a directions card; and a newspaper clipping, "Signs of the Zodiac: Part II - Gemini and Cancer" by Isabel M. Hickey.
- Series: Upstate New York
  - Rhinebeck development study, Spring 1976 (Box 1)
    Created by Cornell University Landscape Architecture Graduate Program
  - Community improvement program: city of Elmira, NY, October 1965 (Box 1)
    Created by Department of Urban Renewal, Elmira, NY
  - General plan: area characteristics, Syracuse NY, February 1967 (Box 1)
    Created by Department of Planning
  - Onondaga County development study, 1960 (?) (Box 1)
    Includes folder of zoning documentation, Onondaga County
  - The regional center: a comprehensive plan for downtown Buffalo, NY, April 1971 (Box 1)
    Created by Wallace, McHarg, Roberts & Todd
  - Twin Bridge redevelopment: Rochester, NY, 1959 (?) (Box 8)
  - Planning central area Syracuse, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Central business district plan: Rome, NY, 1959 (?) (Box 1)
    Created by City Planning Board
  - Plan for Ballston: a comprehensive development guide, 1964 (Box 1)
    Created by Ballston Planning Board; Saratoga County Planning Board
  - A suggested development plan: Elmira-Chemung county metropolitan area. Phase Three: Master plan studies, March 1962 (Box 1)
    Created by Herbert H. Smith Associates, in cooperation with the Chemung County Planning Board
  - Johnson City, NY general plan: a planning study for Johnson City, NY 1958-1959, 1958-9 (Box 1)
  - A master plan for the Massena Area: a report to the New York State Department of Commerce, the Village [and] the Town of Massena, NY, August 1958 (Box 1)
    Created by Thomas W. Mackesey and Sargent-Webster-Crenshaw & Folly, consultants
  - Lysander new community: planning summary, February 1971 (Box 1)
  - New single family housing construction in the urbanized area of Broome County, during the decade 1950-59 and the year 1960, March 1961 (Box 1)
    Created by Broome County Planning Board
  - Rochester gateway study, June 1991 (Box 1)
    Created by Paul Daniel Marriott
    Submitted to the City of Rochester as part of a CU CRP master's thesis
  - A general plan: Town of Dryden, Village of Dryden, Village of Freeville, October 1968 (Box 1)
    Created by Egner & Neiderkorn Associates Inc.
  - Chemung County urban area: studies and plans, June 1965 (Box 1)
    A report of student work in a field problem in urban planning, fall semester 64-65
  - The Buffalo-Amherst corridor technical report, March 1969 (Box 1)
    Created by State of New York Office of Planning Coordination
  - Ithaca urban area: a general plan, October 1959 (Box 8)
    Created by Greater Ithaca Regional Planning Board
  - Downtown design plan: Ithaca, New York, September 1992 (Box 1)
    Created by Roger Trancik, FASLA
  - Ithaca, New York: a general plan, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Town of Ulysses: draft comprehensive land use plan 1999 (Box 1)
    Created by Town of Ulysses Comprehensive Plan Committee and Planning Board
    Draft land use plan map attached
  - Phase two, master plan studies: an economic survey for the Elmira-Chemung County metropolitan area, 1962 (Box 1)
    Created by Herbert H. Smith Associates, NJ
    Prepared for the Chemung County Planning Board
  - Phase four, master plan studies: an effectuation report for the Elmira-Chemung County metropolitan area. Part 1 - Zoning guide. Part 2 - Capital improvements program., March 1962 (Box 1)
  - Transportation in the Onondaga-Syracuse metropolitan area, May 1962 (Box 1)
    Prepared for the Onondaga County Dept. of Planning and the NYS Dept. of Commerce
  - Economic base of the Onondaga-Syracuse metropolitan area, December 1961 (Box 1)
    Created by Blair Associates Planning Consultants and the Bureau of Economic Research, Lemoyne College, Syracuse
    Prepared for the NYS Dept. of Commerce and the Onondaga County Regional Planning Board
  - Utilities in the Onondaga-Syracuse metropolitan area, August 1962 (Box 1)
  - Recreation and open space in the Onondaga-Syracuse metropolitan area, March 1962 (Box 1)
    Prepared for the Onondaga County Dept. of Planning and the NYS Department of Commerce
  - Zoning in the Onondaga-Syracuse metropolitan area, September 1962 (Box 1)
  - Comprehensive development plan, December 1969 (Box 1)
    Created by Herkimer-Oneida Counties Comprehensive Planning Program
  - Future development patterns, Elmira NY: General plan, general plan studies, downtown development study, July 1960 (Box 1)
    Created by Community Planning Associates, Inc.
  - City of Rye, NY 1985 development plan (Box 1)
    Created by City of Rye Planning Commission, with the technical assistance of RPPW Inc.
  - City of Utica 1998-1999 consolidated plan (Box 1)
    Created by Edward A. Hanna, Mayor, and Thomas H. Larrabee, Commissioner of Urban and Economic Development
    Prepared for U.S. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development
  - Target for tomorrow: a master plan for the Endicott urban area, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    Created by Cornell University City and Regional Planning Department
    A study by graduate students
  - City plan of the city of White Plains, NY, September 1928 (Box 1)
    Created by E.P. Goodrich and Robert Whitten
    Includes 4 maps
  - The future of downtown Rochester: a general neighborhood renewal plan for the central business district, 1965 (Box 1)
    Created by City of Rochester
  - The Schoharie Valley townsite: a protected community for the nuclear age, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Millbrook, New York village master plan 1985-2000 (Box 1)
    Created by Village of Millbrook Planning Board with the technical assistance of the Dutchess County Planning Dept.
  - The master plan: Gloversville, NY, 1961 (Box 1)
    Created by City Planning Commission with Russell D. Bailey and Associates
  - A planning study for Johnson City, New York, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Who does the planning? A joint conference of the Upstate New York AIP and the Central Ontario TPIC, September 1964 (Box 2)
    Papers presented at the conference, April 24-25, 1964, Niagara Falls, NY
  - Planning and development: the project and policy report of the Ithaca Department of Planning and Development 1975-77, 1977 (Box 2)
    Created by Ithaca Department of Planning and Development
  - Village of Williamsville master plan and main street corridor development plan, December 1962 (Box 2)
    Created by Economic Consultants Organization, Inc.
  - Town of Hamburg 2010 comprehensive plan (1997 master plan update) (Box 2)
    Created by Wendel
  - Albany-Capital harbour plan, 1980 (?) (Box 2)
    Created by The Associated Planners, and the Temporary State Commission on the Capital City
    2 documents: plan and foldout poster map
  - Broome County urban area: plans and studies, May 1963 (Box 2)
    A report of student work in a field problem in urban planning Fall semester '62-63
  - Comprehensive plan: city of New Rochelle, New York, July 1996 (Box 2)
    Created by Comprehensive Plan Advisory Committee; New Rochelle Dept. of Development; Saccardi & Schiff, Inc.
    Copy
  - Planning report: town of Ulysses, New York, 1959 (Box 2)
    Created by Thomas W. Mackesey and Sargent-Webster-Crenshaw & Folley, Architects, AIA
  - Cayuga County land use plan, 1997 (Box 2)
    Created by Dave Miller, Cayuga County Planning Department
    In binder
  - Master plan or comprehensive development plan for the city of Saratoga Springs, New York, June 1987 (Box 2)
    Created by Saratoga Springs Planning Board
    copy
  - Evaluation of regional land use schemes, June 1971 (Box 2)
    Created by Central New York Regional Planning and Development Board
    Report no. CNYRPDB-RS-71-HUD-229-02 "unofficial preliminary report"
  - Rome master plan: summary report 1970-1990 (Box 2)
    Created by Oneida County Department of Planning
    Foldout poster with land use map
  - Community planning: the general community plan, May 1960 (Box 2)
    Created by Bureau of Planning, Division of Economic Development, Department of Commerce, State of New York
  - Control of land subdivision: a manual of subdivision regulations for municipal officials, subdivision developers and planning boards, 1968 (Box 2)
    Created by Office of Planning Coordination, State of New York
  - Preliminary sketch plan: Elmira-Chemung County, NY (figure 34), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Various reproductions of map
  - New York state canal recreationway plan: executive summary, June 1995 (Box 2)
    Created by Beyer Blinder Belle Consortium
  - New York state canal revitalization program, August 1996 (Box 2)
    Created by NYS Thruway Authority/Canal Corporation
  - The future of central city, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
    Created by Cornell University
    Organization of Cornell Planners 6th Annual Conference: proceedings
  - Historic Ithaca and Tompkins County newsletter, Fall 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Created by Historic Ithaca
  - UDC in Albany, NY, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Brochure
  - UDC and housing policy, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - UDC in Buffalo, NY, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - UDC in Rochester, NY, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - UDC and the private sector, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - UDC in Niagara Falls, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Renaissance on the Genesee", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Created by Ogden Tanner
    Reprint of article in Architectural Forum, July 1959
  - Quality of the physical environment: goals and programs (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Typed list; mentions Owasco Outlet
  - Thoroughfare plan, Auburn NY, September 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Created by Candeub, Cabot and Associates
    Map. In mailing envelope from Beardsley and Beardsley, Architects
  - "Proposed Auburn Arterial Meets Opposition", September 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Created by Syracuse Herald-Journal
    Newspaper clipping from Sept. 28, 1962. In mailing envelope from Beardsley and Beardsley, Architects
- Series: Western US
  - South Bayshore study: a proposed development plan, June 1969 (Box 8)
    Created by Department of City Planning, City and County of San Francisco
  - Castro Valley central business district specific plan, August 1983 (Box 8)
    Created by Alameda County Planning Commission; Castro Valley Municipal Advisory Council
  - Irvine: Progress 1971 (Box 5)
    Created by The Irvine Company
  - The redevelopment plan for the Golden Gateway: Embarcadero-Lower Market approved redevelopment project area E-1, April 1959 (Box 8)
    Created by Redevelopment Agency of the City and County of San Francisco
    Foldout maps attached
  - San Francisco urban design study preliminary report 1: Background, March 1969 (Box 5)
    Created by San Francisco Department of City Planning
  - Watsonville, CA: an evaluation of development potential and downtown redevelopment strategies for the City of Watsonville, March 1990 (Box 5)
    Created by Urban Land Institute
    A panel advisory service report
  - Downtown Santa Cruz: an evaluation of development potential and redevelopment strategies for the Pacific Garden Mall Area of Santa Cruz, California, March 1960 (Box 5)
  - General plan proposal for the Portola Valley area, San Mateo County, California, September 1964 (Box 5)
    Created by William Spangle and Associates
    Prepared for the San Mateo County Planning Commission. Maps in back envelope.
  - Diamond Heights: a report on the tentative redevelopment plan, November 1951 (Box 5)
    Created by Redevelopment Agency of the City and County of San Francisco; San Francisco Department of City Planning
  - Redevelopment in Diamond Heights, March 1950 (Box 5)
  - Oakland Chinatown redevelopment project: a proposal, November 1965 (Box 5)
    Created by Warren W. Jones & Associates et al.
  - Environmental goals for the Los Angeles region, July 1967 (Box 5)